Hi, my name is Brian Caffo and, I'm in the
Department of
Biostatistics at the Bloomberg School of
Public Health at Johns Hopkins University.
And this is the Coursera data science
specialization class on RStudio Presenter.
This class is co-taught with my
instructors, Jeff Leek and Roger Peng.
Okay.
So what is RStudio Presenter?
Let me get a nice high lighter here.
So RStudio created this authoring tool so
that
you can create reproducible presentations
within their environment.
And basically if you're familiar with
slidify, then,
you should have zero effort for picking
this up.
And if you're not familiar with slidify, I
think
this is probably a little bit easier to
learn.
So, just like Slidify code is author,
authored in a
generalized mark down format that allows
for R code chunks.
And the ultimate output is an html5
presentation that you view in a web
browser.
The file index for the presenter file is,
has
a .Rpres extension instead of .md .r mark
down Extension
like and slidify and then there's a lot of
GUI tools, and we will go through them in,
the
environment that you can use that makes,
you know,
this quite nice, if you like to use GUI
tools,
and maybe if you like to do a lot of
command lines stuff maybe slidify would be
better for you.
Okay.
So the guide that you probably want to
follow is, on this link right here.
Go to that guide, it's, very good.
Most of this content is just taken from
that link and I, created this
presentation in, RStudio Presenter so you
could get a sense what it looks like.
The Quick start is just you do File, and
then New File then R presentation and if
you're you know, keystroke junkie, then
that's just Alt-f, then f, then p.
And then you just start using
Slidify/knitr style Cmd for authoring
content.
They walk you through they, they have all
these things that will help walk you
through it.
You know, so, single quotes for inline
code.
Triple quotes for block code.
And, same options as, you know, for code
evaluation catch.
Okay.
So here's my, presentation that I was
working on, for today.
And, you can see here in the preview pane
here.
Here's the The preview what I could, do,
is if I wanted to,
I could pop this whole thing out into a
oh, where am I at?
There we go, into a bigger
bigger screen.
If you, click on this button over here
more, it'll, show that you can
view it in the browser, you can save it as
a web page, you can publish it to RPubs.
This clears the cache, from the R Code
that you ran.
and, you know, this navigates through.
Then, if you're at a slide that you want,
and you click on Edit.
It brings you to that, location in the
slide over there.
okay, so let's just show you how to, how
to get started.
So you would just go to File > New File.
New file > R Presentation.
And then it, it creates one.
And I'll just create one called [SOUND]
test.
Okay.
There it is.
And so now, if I say this is my, my test
presentation.
[SOUND] Brian Caffo [SOUND] and the date
is, I
don't know let's just put the R date in
there.
So we'll just do date [SOUND] like that.
Okay.
And then when I save it, watch what
happens.
It compiles it, my test presentation,
Brian Caffo, puts the date in there.
Okay.
Then you can see how the, authoring looks
an awful lot like just ordinary old.
Mark down or Slidify like we've done
before.
You can see right here, where you have
some separated out R code.
So look, it'll look like that where it
reproduces the code and then puts it in
there.
You know, and of course it takes the same
subset of commands as Knitter and Slidify.
So if I did echo equals false.
Right, and then save it, it reruns it, and
there now, it's no longer, echoing the,
Cmd, okay?
And then, it shows you how you can, add
in plots, and that sort of, that's sort of
thing.
So during this presentation what I'm just
going to
go through, is all the options you can go.
These, these equal signs separate the
slides.
You actually only need three of them,
right?
So if I do that, it, gives me that.
But I take away down to two, it messes up,
right?
Okay, so, you need three of them.
And it gives the correct, correct slide
transition.
Okay, but, another, and, so it's a, and
then
if you want help by the way, Markdown
Markdown
Quick Reference, you can click on that
right there
and just see, your Markdown Quick
Reference right there.